<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.63.1">Hugo</generator><title type="html"><![CDATA[review on KevOps]]></title>
    
    
    
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HTML" />
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review/index.xml" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml" title="RSS" />
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Atom" />
    <updated>2020-01-25T16:20:07+01:00</updated>
    
    
    
    
        <id>https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review/</id>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week 10, 11, 12, 13]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/04/2017-week-10-11-12-13/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/03/2017-week-8-and-9/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week 8 and 9" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-seven/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week seven" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week five" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week four" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week three" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/04/2017-week-10-11-12-13/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-04-02T13:34:13+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-04-02T13:34:13+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Time sure does fly sometimes! I just realized the last &ldquo;weekly&rdquo; review post was from the beginning of march, namely <a href="/2017-week-8-and-9/">week 8 and 9</a>, so one month ago. In the meantime I played a lot of <a href="http://amzn.to/2msN60T">The Legend Of Zelda: Breath Of The Wild</a>, worked on a Go thing, and went to a concert.</p>
<h2 id="breath-of-the-wild">Breath Of The Wild</h2>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/weeks-march/link-death-mountain.jpg"
      alt="Link looking onto Death Mountain"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Link looking onto Death Mountain
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>I am absolutely in love with Breath Of The Wild. It&rsquo;s such a well made, high-quality game and I can hardly but the <a href="http://amzn.to/2lLRcN1">Nintendo Switch</a> down. Running around and exploring the open areas, climbing mountains, finding <a href="http://zelda.wikia.com/wiki/Korok">Korok</a> hidden everywhere around - it&rsquo;s just fun! I enjoy running around with no aim for hours and finding new things.</p>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/weeks-march/finding-a-korok.jpg"
      alt="Korok are hidden everywhere around Hyrule"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Korok are hidden everywhere around Hyrule
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>Beside spending hours climbing up mountains to find all my little Korok friends I also conquered three of the four <a href="http://zelda.wikia.com/wiki/Divine_Beast">Divine Beasts</a>. The last one missing is <a href="http://zelda.wikia.com/wiki/Vah_Naboris">Vah Naboris</a>, a gigantic camel. I think until <a href="http://amzn.to/2nNCGZA">Elder Scrolls Online: Morrowind</a> is released I will spent all my time running through Hyrule. I cannot recommend Breath Of The Wild enough - it&rsquo;s fantastic!</p>
<h2 id="thelinkclub">TheLink.club</h2>
<p>Some time ago I bought the domain <a href="http://thelink.club">thelink.club</a> - it&rsquo;s currently empty but I am working on something more or less actively. It&rsquo;s a HTTP based API for saving and sharing links in a collaborative way. The basic idea is that I&rsquo;ll write browser extensions for Chrome, Firefox, Safari, and maybe IE from which you can sent links to an API endpoint. Links are then saved inside MongoDB and can be queried or read out over HTTP. This way the LinkClub lists can be output into a variety of systems using techniques like Ajax.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s a great way to get into Go / Microservice programming with Go and I already learned quite a lot about using the http package in Go. I enjoy working with Go; It&rsquo;s challenging and new to me. Coming from languages like JavaScript and PHP I enjoy the strictness and the good compiler - and compiler errors - while developing. I might write down a bit of what I learned along the way as a new Go user and what was challenging coming from JavaScript or PHP.</p>
<h2 id="völkerball">Völkerball</h2>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/weeks-march/volkerball-fog-show.jpg"
      alt="What looks like a burning person is actually just fog. 😐"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      What looks like a burning person is actually just fog. 😐
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p><a href="http://www.voelkerball.eu/">Völkerball</a> is a Rammstein Cover band and I had the pleasure to see them live. They not only have a full stage setup similar to older shows by Rammstein, they also have a lead singer with a voice similar to Till Lindemann which makes the entire experience of seeing them a lot better. The concert was around 2-2.5h of an amazing live performance with costume changes and a &ldquo;choreography&rdquo; similar to what Rammstein performs on stage - minus the fire show. For &ldquo;Mein Teil&rdquo; they even had the kettle. If you&rsquo;re into Rammstein and get the chance to see Völkerball live do it! It&rsquo;s well worth it.</p>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/weeks-march/volkerball-mein-teil.jpg"
      alt="Costume during performance of “Mein Teil”"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Costume during performance of “Mein Teil”
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>Alright, that&rsquo;s it. See you next month or week or whatever. 👋</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week 8 and 9]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/03/2017-week-8-and-9/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-seven/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week seven" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week five" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week four" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week three" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week two" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/03/2017-week-8-and-9/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-03-05T19:43:16+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-03-05T19:43:16+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It turns out that a lot of my time is actually spent working or playing games - so there&rsquo;s not too much to tell and weekly updates become hard-ish to write. I am going to go with bi-weekly or even monthly updates from now on. So this post is week eight and week nine - week nine being the week the <a href="http://amzn.to/2lLRcN1">Nintendo Switch</a> and <a href="http://amzn.to/2msN60T">The Legend Of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a> were released.</p>
<h2 id="antilopen-gang">Antilopen Gang</h2>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/week-eight-nine/antilopen-gang-schlachthof-wiesbaden.jpg"
      alt="Antilopen Gang live at Schlachthof Wiesbaden"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Antilopen Gang live at Schlachthof Wiesbaden
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>I had the pleasure to see German Hip-Hop/Rap band <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antilopen_Gang">Antilopen Gang</a> live for the first time and I was simply blown away. I expected a rather chill concert but got one and a half hours of full blown Hip-Hop and Punk. The Punk elements are &ldquo;new&rdquo; within their music and I love it. I can&rsquo;t wait for the next time I will be able to see them live. 5/7 would recommend. 👍</p>
<h2 id="nintendo-switch">Nintendo Switch</h2>
<p>As I mentioned I pre-ordered the <a href="http://amzn.to/2lLRcN1">Nintendo Switch</a> and I am in love with it. As expected the Switch is a solid and beautifully made device. It might be a <em>bit</em> to big for in-hand playing but I got used to it after a few hours. I got Breath of the Wild, the newest title in the <em>The Legend Of Zelda</em> series with the switch and have been playing it four roughly 10 hours.</p>
<h2 id="the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild">The Legend Of Zelda: Breath Of The Wild</h2>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/week-eight-nine/link-standing-around.jpg"
      alt="Link standing around in Kakariko Village"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Link standing around in Kakariko Village
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>I am madly in love. The last time I fell so quickly for a Zelda game was when I first played Majora’s Mask (still my favorite in the series) which I could not let go for a minute. Of course the first things I did was running around and finding out how things work and what the game has to offer, collection everything I found like apples, monster parts, and weapons. Story-wise I found the first Shrines, which are tiny trials (=_puzzles_) one needs to solve to gain a Spirit Orb. Apparently, there are no heart containers to collect like in previous games. Spirit Orbs can be traded at shrines to the gods. If Link has enough they offer to trade 4 Spirit Orbs for either a Heart Container or a Stamina vessel, increasing either the number of Hearts or the Stamina available.</p>
<p>New in Breath Of The Wild is food cooking. Food can be cooked by finding a cooking pot. To cook food you need to open the menu (<em>+</em>), and then select the ingredient and select &ldquo;Hold&rdquo; - up to five ingredients can be put into a pot for cooking. If the ingredients are combined correctly a elexir or dish is the result, as shown below.</p>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/week-eight-nine/breath-of-the-wild-cooking-food.jpg"
      alt="Cooking Food"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Cooking Food
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>The cooked food restores more health and - based on ingredients - grands additional effects like increased armor, speed, or stealth. I like this system and it&rsquo;s fun to experiment with different ingredients.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s it for week 8 and 9. See you next week. Or the week after. 👋</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week seven]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-seven/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week five" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week four" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week three" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week two" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week one" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-seven/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-02-18T14:03:26+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-02-18T14:03:26+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In week six nothing happened so it was skipped. Quite nice, actually. In the second half of week six and through week seven I prepared a workshop which I gave on Friday at the <a href="https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Frankfurt-Developers/events/237066551/">Coding Night</a>. This Coding Night was a special one: The topic was &ldquo;CodingNight feat. CodeDoor feat. Refugees&rdquo; which was a collaboration between <a href="https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/Frankfurt-Developers/">CodingNight</a> and <a href="http://codedoor.org/">CodeDoor</a>. CodeDoor is a project which teaches Refugees coding skills, how to build projects and how to get a Job in the programming field. I jumped at the chance to get a spot and share my knowledge so I prepared a Workshop on how to build your own Website with Jekyll and GitHub. Sadly due to problems with the different operating systems we could not finish the workshop and in the end &ldquo;only&rdquo; installed Git at every device. I would like to continue my workshop and finish it over time. Maybe at the next Coding Night which I should join more often!</p>
<p>If you want you can take a look at the <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1F6Xi-zF0YjaQ7q85Ot6jtrrMVD0njcBijXOqNDsM57Y/edit?usp=sharing">Presentation</a> or the <a href="https://lab.kevingimbel.me/workshop/2017/coding-night-x-code-door/">Workshop Material I wrote</a>.</p>
<h3 id="sum41">sum41</h3>
<p>I saw sum41 live for the first time ever. When I was younger I liked their music a lot but never had the chance to see them. So this Thursday my girlfriend, a friend, and I went to my favorite concert venue, <a href="https://schlachthof-wiesbaden.de/">Schlachthof Wiesbaden</a>. I did not expect too much from the concert and was surprised how good they actually are. They played a variety of old and new songs and I can recommend going to a concert near you if it isn&rsquo;t sold out already.</p>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/week-seven/sum41-schlachthof-wiesbaden.jpg"
      alt="A bad mobile photograph from the concert."
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      A bad mobile photograph from the concert.
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>Surprisingly for a punk concert there was a hell of a light show throughout the concert.</p>
<p>And that&rsquo;s it. See you next week (or not). 👋</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week five]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week four" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week three" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week two" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week one" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2016, a short review" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-02-08T08:51:13+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-02-08T08:51:13+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another week passed, another personal review. This week I finally got a appointment with my tattoo artist to finish up my tattoo. I&rsquo;m only 6 months late to do so because I kept saying &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll call next week&rdquo;, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll do it when I&rsquo;m back from Amsterdam&rdquo;, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll do it after Christmas&rdquo; - and so on. I am really bad with managing time and work-life balance. If you have any tips on how you manage the things you have to do, hit me up <a href="https://twitter.com/_kevinatari">on twitter @_kevinatari</a>.</p>
<h3 id="go-">Go 💻</h3>
<p>You might know I am learning Go at the moment. I build a new thingy, <code>Colog</code>, which is a log helper that supports a basic configuration and produced colorful terminal logs. It&rsquo;s still in its early phase and there&rsquo;s a lot more I want to implement - I just don&rsquo;t know how because I am not yet fluent in Go. The project is open-sourced on GitHub at <a href="https://github.com/kevingimbel/colog">kevingimbel/colog</a>.</p>
<h3 id="moving-">Moving 📦</h3>
<p>I spent my Saturday helping my girlfriend move to her new flat which was exhausting. Nonetheless I enjoyed it somehow, moving is hard work and it&rsquo;s a good feeling to sit in a filled flat after moving all the stuff around all day. I like it. Don&rsquo;t ask me to help you move, tho. &lt;3</p>
<p>On Thursday and Friday I spent all my work time with Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Elasticsearch. My Elasticsearch cluster is now running and I try to get log files into it with <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/logstash">Logstash</a> and <a href="https://www.elastic.co/products/beats">Beats</a>. The last problem to solve is that the parsing of log files appears to be really hard. Logstash has a &ldquo;language&rdquo; for parsing files called <a href="https://www.elastic.co/guide/en/logstash/current/plugins-filters-grok.html#_grok_basics"><code>grok</code></a> which basically is a variable-to-regex system. It&rsquo;s rather complicated. At the moment I do not understand it and I do not get it to properly parse my log files. I guess that&rsquo;s a thing for the next week - getting Logstash up and running.</p>
<h3 id="politics-and-stuff-">Politics and stuff 🏴</h3>
<p>The current situation around the globe troubles me a lot. It&rsquo;s draining me out and I have to stop consuming news and (twitter) feeds from time to time. The issue with Trump going mental in America and the slow but steady rise of facist parties across Europe is too depressing to constantly follow it. I got a pay rise in January and I decided to support independent journalism and Antifa and left-wing movements with it instead if putting all aside. First on the list are Corrective and Streetcoverage. I need to do more research on who I want to support and how I can support them. I also made <a href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/825810866377469953">a Twitter Moment</a> with some of the tweets I liked this week. Hint: It&rsquo;s political.</p>
<p>Related to current events I also started playing Skyrim again, this time on the XBox One with Mods. It&rsquo;s a great escape for me because I love the world and lore of Skyrim and for a few hours I can forget everything that troubles me.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s it for week five. See you next week! 🙋</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week four]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week three" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week two" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week one" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2016, a short review" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/11/farewell-jekyll-hello-hugo/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Farewell Jekyll, Hello Hugo" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-01-29T12:44:43+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-01-29T12:44:43+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s the last week of the first month already - weird how fast time seems to tick! This week has been rather stressful and loaded with work which is why I did not write any posts or did any programming in my free time. Looking back at the week there&rsquo;s not much to say so this will be a quick read with some reading recommendations at the end.</p>
<h3 id="dep"><code>dep</code></h3>
<p>The Go language has released a alpha version of <a href="https://github.com/golang/dep"><code>dep</code></a> - their dependency management tool. Up until now there was no native suport for dependency management in Go. Go provides an <code>import</code> functionality to load packages. The <code>import</code> mechanism is similar to the NodeJS <code>require</code> - with the big difference that it used to store all packages inside the <code>$GOPATH</code> - a directory on the system where all packages from all go code is stored. With the new <code>dep</code> dependency manager dependencies will be stored inside a <code>vendor</code> directory inside the package directory - similar to <code>node_modules</code>.</p>
<p>I started playing around with the alpha release and will write a article about it once I gathered enough information.</p>
<h3 id="crypt-of-the-necrodancer">Crypt of the Necrodancer</h3>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-HiQUw5Np8o" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>My best friend showed me <a href="http://necrodancer.com/">Crypt of the NecroDancer</a>, a rhythmic, rouge-like, dungeon crawler where you dance your way deep into a dungeon. It&rsquo;s beautiful. Weird, and beautiful. You have to stay in the rhythm to move around and attack enemies. The more you stay in rhythm the better your score gets. Typical for rouge-like games when you die you need to start over. I only played for an hour or so but look forward to continue it. It&rsquo;s more casual which is what I need - or want - to play at the moment. I bought it for PlayStation 4 but its also available on PS Vita, Mac, PC, and iOS.</p>
<h3 id="antilopen-gang">Antilopen Gang</h3>
<p>I bought tickets for <a href="http://www.schlachthof-wiesbaden.de/programmdetails/items/antilopen-gang-anarchie-alltag.html">Antilopen Gang</a>. Antilopen Gang is german Hip Hop - and Punk, at least on their latest album <a href="https://play.google.com/music/m/Bl6aukayea54w6hm757vx2npv3m?t=Anarchie_und_Alltag__Bonusalbum_Atombombe_auf_Deutschland_-_Antilopen_Gang">&ldquo;Anarchie und Alltag&rdquo;</a>. I am looking forward to the concert!</p>
<h3 id="things-to-read">Things to read</h3>
<p><a href="https://code.facebook.com/posts/557147474482256/this-browser-tweak-saved-60-of-requests-to-facebook">&ldquo;This browser tweak saved 60% of requests to Facebook&rdquo;</a> - how Facebook worked with browser vendors to tweak the browser cache, effectively saving 60% of requests to Servers.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2017/1/26/14398934/tim-scully-lsd-chemistry-drugs-counterculture-psychedelics">&ldquo;Here’s how underground chemist Tim Scully planned to save the world with LSD&rdquo;</a> the Story of Tim Scully who produced LSD in the 60s in underground labs. It&rsquo;s an interesting read into the world of psychedelics and LSD production - which appears to be really hard.</p>
<p>I made a <a href="https://twitter.com/i/moments/825722790259126273">Twitter Moment</a> with some tweets I found interesting. Most tweets are political and represents feedback to Trumps shit show. It&rsquo;s horrible how much he fucked up in just one week - stay anti, USA! 🏴</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s it for week four. Next week I will help my girlfriend move to her new flat and hopefully finally get to my tattoo artist so we can arrange a session to finish up my tattoo - which is long overdue.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week three]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week two" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week one" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2016, a short review" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/11/farewell-jekyll-hello-hugo/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Farewell Jekyll, Hello Hugo" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-01-22T11:44:43+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-01-22T11:44:43+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another week another short review! The third week of 2017 had a lot of travel because I attended an <a href="https://elastic.co">Elasticsearch</a> training course in Munich to learn more about Elasticsearch hands-on. The two day course was exiting and I enjoyed my time, learning quite a lot about the different features of Elasticsearch and Kibana. Part of the course material is a 500 page PDF file which is a copy of the presentation held during the two days - I am glad I got it because it&rsquo;s a great reference to look at.</p>
<h3 id="munich">Munich</h3>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2017/week-three/snow-covered-bicycle-munich.jpg"
      alt="Snow covered bicycle in Munich."
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Snow covered bicycle in Munich.
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>Munich was cold with -7°C to -10°C and there was a lot of snow - for a few days it was nice but I&rsquo;m happy to be back in the middle of Germany without snow. I stayed at <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/197005">an Airbnb</a> because all hotels around the city were booked due to a big conference in town. If you want to visit Munich check out the above room - it&rsquo;s great!</p>
<p>During my trip to and from Munich I also had to work at a Starbucks and on the train. Both places are not perfect for working if you&rsquo;re used to a second monitor and having space around you. Starbucks was also really loud which can get annoying - good thing there&rsquo;s music! What helped me tremendously was the MacBook battery life. I can get an average of 8-10 hours of battery life which is simply astonishing.</p>
<h3 id="open-source">Open source</h3>
<p>I also helped <a href="https://github.com/spf13/hugo/issues/2946">track down a bug</a> with Gulp and hugo, and then decided to tweet what I have been doing for the past two month: <a href="https://twitter.com/_kevinatari/status/821773139617218562">Following an open source project</a></p>
<p>Following an open source project is quite interesting. I read a lot of the hugo issue reports and look at the Pull Requests submitted. This helps me see how to handle pull requests and open source and in my opinion <a href="https://github.com/spf13/hugo">the hugo project</a> is a good example.</p>
<h3 id="star-trek">Star Trek</h3>
<p>I finished The Original Series and now started to watch The Next Generation. It&rsquo;s the first time I watch everything in the correct order and I&rsquo;m exited!</p>
<p>I also programmed a bit and build a text to 1337speak converter <a href="https://github.com/kevingimbel/leetscript">node module</a> and a <a href="https://github.com/kevingimbel/leetscript-cli">cli tool</a> which uses the first module. I&rsquo;m not yet sure why you would need this type of one-way converter but it was an interesting task to build a node module, publish it, and then use it in a script - I&rsquo;ll try and wrap it up in a post.</p>
<p>I also wrote a blog post about <a href="/deploy-a-static-site-with-git/">deploying a site with git</a> - which is what I am doing with my website at the moment.</p>
<h3 id="not-on-tour">Not On Tour</h3>
<p>On Friday I saw <a href="https://notontour.bandcamp.com/">Not On Tour</a> live with my girlfriend. Not On Tour is a Punk / Hardcore Punk Band from Tel Aviv and I loved every bit of the concerts. The concert was in a small venue with around 50-100 people and they sounded a bit harder live then I expected - and a lot more powerful. I would recommend seeing them live whenever you get a chance. <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/BPhmT5rgJvw/?taken-by=kevingimbel">Here&rsquo;s a little Instagram video</a>.</p>
<h3 id="links">Links</h3>
<p>Here are some interesting things from this week:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HTD-FJVY9rE">All Fallout Intros, 1997-2015</a> - seeing all the intros to one of my favorite game series is great.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2017/1/19/14258474/trump-inauguration-science-politics-climate-change-vaccines">Yes, science is political</a> - The Verge on why science is political and how science and politics play together. A sad read in the upcome of &ldquo;Trumps America&rdquo;.</p>
<p><a href="https://medium.com/basecs/bits-bytes-building-with-binary-13cb4289aafa#.3n5g6mfdr">Bits, Bytes, Building With Binary</a> by <a href="https://medium.com/@vaidehijoshi">Vaidehi Joshi</a> - a post about bits and bytes and how they work. Vaidehi started a series called <a href="https://medium.com/basecs">basecs</a> which aims to explain how computers actually work. I highly recommend reading it!</p>
<p><a href="http://kunststube.net/encoding/">What Every Programmer Absolutely, Positively Needs To Know About Encodings And Character Sets To Work With Text</a> by David Zentgraf - an interesting read about handling encoding and how encoding works.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week two]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2017, week one" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2016, a short review" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/11/farewell-jekyll-hello-hugo/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Farewell Jekyll, Hello Hugo" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-01-15T17:05:13+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-01-15T17:05:13+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I spent a lot of time with Amazon Web Services, or AWS, and made myself familiar with the backend and the way server / instance management works on AWS. While doing so I also learned that AWS instances are by default not accessible from the internet - they have no open ports and each instance needs a &ldquo;Security Group&rdquo; which defines ways to access the instance. They also do not have Shell access by default. When you&rsquo;ve never worked with AWS the pure amount of options is overwhelming. I felt like endlessly reading through documentations until I had everything setup correctly. It was quite a task and I&rsquo;m sure the next time I need to setup an AWS instance it will go smoother. I might cover what I&rsquo;ve learned in a blog post once I am &ldquo;done&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I played a bit of recore and Dragon Age: Inquisition but I am not in the mood to play too much video games at the moment. After spending hundreds of hours in The Elder Scrolls: Online last year I feel it&rsquo;s good to have my controller rest for a while. I did spent time watching Star Trek tho. I am almost finished with The Original Series and in fact it&rsquo;s the first time ever I watched it episode by episode.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.giphy.com/l2R03nrt5LDkpc6VG.gif" alt="&ldquo;Spock jamming in space&rdquo;"></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m looking forward to continuing with The Next Generation once I&rsquo;m finished with The Original Series. You can probably tell I really like Star Trek. 🖖 I am also looking forward to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Trek:_Discovery">Star Trek: Discovery</a>.</p>
<p>I wrote two articles, <a href="https://kevingimbel.com/bash-script-ws/">&ldquo;Bash script: ws&rdquo;</a> and <a href="https://kevingimbel.com/writing-nodejs-cli-tools/">&ldquo;Writing NodeJS cli tools&rdquo;</a> which both focus on the command line and command line tools - one time in shell script and one time in NodeJS. I plan to write more articles about both since it&rsquo;s a topic I am interested in.
I also <a href="https://github.com/kevingimbel/kevingimbel.com/issues?utf8=%E2%9C%93&amp;q=is%3Aissue%20is%3Aclosed%20created%3A2017-01-08..2017-01-15%20">fixed an issue</a> I introduced due to bad CSS scoping. Always check your scope!</p>
<p>Next week I will be in Munich, Germany to attend a Elastic course about Elasticsearch and relevant products. I&rsquo;m exited and I&rsquo;m looking forward to the 2-day course.</p>
<p><strong>Other things:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>I pre-ordered the <a href="http://amzn.to/2izPQqn">Nintendo Switch</a> and <a href="http://amzn.to/2jygmPp">The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild</a> and I&rsquo;m exited!</li>
<li><em>Yo no hablo español, soy aprendendio español!</em> I started learning Spanish again. 🎉</li>
<li>I cooked vegan curry and accidentally made so much I could eat it all week. I&rsquo;m now taking a Curry break.</li>
<li>I learned <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/searching-issues/">GitHub has great advanced search options</a></li>
<li>The xx released their third Studio Album called &ldquo;I see you&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s fantastic. (Listen: <a href="https://play.google.com/music/listen?u=0#/album//The+xx/I+See+You">Google Play Music</a> / <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/2PXy9USZAoTSdtrxfkPBnl">Spotify</a>)</li>
</ul>
<p>That&rsquo;s it for week two. 👋</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017, week one]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="2016, a short review" />
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/11/farewell-jekyll-hello-hugo/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Farewell Jekyll, Hello Hugo" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-01-08T18:02:48+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-01-08T18:02:48+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>German <a href="http://uarrr.org/">blogger</a>, <a href="http://marcel.io/">designer</a>, and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/rrradiovisiontv/">YouTuber</a> Marcel Wichmann started a <a href="http://uarrr.org/2017/01/08/rrruckblick-kalenderwoche-152-2017/">weekly-review blog series</a> which I find quite interesting! Reviewing in short what happened in each week of the year is a nice and &ldquo;easy&rdquo; way to recap everything that happened - and it also helps writing this years big review post at the end of the year. I am not sure if I&rsquo;ll keep it up for each week but I will try. So, here&rsquo;s week one.</p>
<h3 id="new-years-resolution">New Year&rsquo;s resolution</h3>
<p>I am not sure where this tradition comes from, but in Germany (and most western countries as far as I know), it&rsquo;s a thing to set goals for the new year. It&rsquo;s basically like a To-Do List for the coming year with things one wants to change.</p>
<p>My New Year&rsquo;s resolution are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Read more books - 12 is my minimum</li>
<li>Loose weight again</li>
<li>Eat more healthy and cook more healthy</li>
<li>Write more blog posts</li>
<li>Program on a regular basis in my free time</li>
<li>Go out more often</li>
<li>Stop smoking cigarettes</li>
</ul>
<p>So far I started reading again before going to bed. I&rsquo;m reading <a href="http://amzn.to/2i3bi8A">&ldquo;The Humans&rdquo;</a> by Matt Haig now, which my girlfriend recommended. So far I like it a lot and I&rsquo;ll write a review once I am finished - which happens to fulfills another point.</p>
<p>Since I work from home I can cook every day. This week so far I cooked fresh vegetables every day, mostly with rice or noodles. I also cooked vegetable stock from leftovers which I can now use for next weeks cooking. 😊</p>
<p>To start the year I wrote a review of last year. It&rsquo;s probably not too interesting for most people but I like to look back at year-in-review posts and I will now write them every year.</p>
<p>As for smoking - well. I try to switch to electronic cigarettes first and then lower the nicotine. It&rsquo;s not going too well at the moment but I continue to try it.</p>
<h3 id="geschlechterkampf">Geschlechterkampf</h3>
<p>On saturday I went to the <a href="http://www.staedelmuseum.de/de/ausstellungen/geschlechterkampf">Geschlechterkampf</a> exhibition at the Städel Museum, my favorite museum in Frankfurt by the way. Overall the exhibition was good and I enjoyed the art from various artists. In particular <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Collier_(painter)">John Collier</a> impressed me and I greatly enjoyed the works exhibited. His painting <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Clytemnestra_by_John_Collier,_1882.jpg">Clytemnestra</a> looks astonishing in full size. Another artists I did not know before is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeanne_Mammen">Jeanne Mammen</a>, an artist from Berlin, Germany. A small room was dedicated to her watercolor paintings.I liked the simplicity in her art; Every image seemed to tell a story.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;re around Frankfurt make sure to see the exhibition. If you&rsquo;re not, you can see some artworks and read background information in the Städel <a href="http://geschlechterkampf.staedelmuseum.de/en/">digital editorial online</a>.</p>
<h3 id="recore">recore</h3>
<p>I started playing <a href="http://amzn.to/2irOziJ">recore</a>, an XBox One exclusive game in which you awake on Far Eden, an desert-like planet. Accompanied by your robot companion Mack you start exploring this &ldquo;dead&rdquo; planet just to realize there are corrupted robots running around. The story seems to resolve around finding out what happened to the robots who should build the planets surface, facilities, and living spaces for the humans.</p>
<h3 id="star-trek">Star Trek</h3>
<p>I started re-watching Star Trek beginning with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Star_Trek:_The_Original_Series">The Original Series</a>. It&rsquo;s inspiring to see the future these screenwriters have imagined. You might not know but a lot of todays technology such as MP3, Smartphones, and Voice Control were originally inspired by Star Trek. There is a documentary about it, and I think the one I saw some years ago is <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZjlF_iSo1Og">this one with William Shatner</a>.</p>
<p>Well that&rsquo;s it for this week. 👍</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016, a short review]]></title>
            <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
            
                <link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/11/farewell-jekyll-hello-hugo/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Farewell Jekyll, Hello Hugo" />
            
                <id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/</id>
            
            
            <published>2017-01-01T14:37:28+01:00</published>
            <updated>2017-01-01T14:37:28+01:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2016 has been an odd year in regards to world events and deaths - quite depressing actually. For me personal it has been the exact opposite. Overall, for me 2016 has been an excellent year.</p>
<h3 id="january">January</h3>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2016-review/january-fuerteventura.jpg"
      alt="View from the hotel in Fuerteventura."
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      View from the hotel in Fuerteventura.
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>January started with what we call a &ldquo;Braincamp&rdquo;. A Braincamp is a company trip to a remote location where we at Synoa GmbH take time outside the office and come up with ideas and projects to do for the year. For 2016 we traveled to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fuerteventura">Fuerteventura</a> which had a wonderful warm climate compared to the cold German January. We spent a week tinkering and researching different ideas and in the end an idea stuck out: <a href="https://bug.industries/">Bug Industries</a> - a card game for developers which we eventually took to <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/timpietrusky/bug-industries-a-card-dice-game-for-us-it-nerds?ref=card">Kickstarter</a>. Unfortunately we did not meet our goal and as of now the project is at rest.</p>
<h3 id="february-and-march">February and March</h3>
<p>February and March were both occupied by work for clients and work on Bug Industries as well as dating somebody who became very special to me over the year.</p>
<p>Researching Kickstarter campaigns, researching social media activities, forming the campaign and general design and illustrations of the game - all these things happened in February and March. Together with <a href="http://herzblutundbock.de/">Herzblut &amp; Bock</a> we brought Bug Industries to live and started the Kickstarter Campaign on March 9th 2016. In the end the project did not cut the goal and we had to cancel it. As mentioned before it&rsquo;s on hold at the moment.</p>
<h3 id="april">April</h3>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2016-review/april-happy-show.jpg"
      alt="Toilet signs at The Happy Show"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Toilet signs at The Happy Show
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>In April I saw the Rammstein Cover Band &ldquo;Stammheim&rdquo; with my best friend. Stammheim did an amazing performance and I&rsquo;m happy I attended the concert - I&rsquo;d see them live again by any chance I get.
Also in April I went to see <a href="http://www.museumangewandtekunst.de/de/museum/ausstellungen/stefan-sagmeister-the-happy-show.html">&ldquo;The Happy Show&rdquo;</a> by Stefan Sagmeister, a Austrian designer who has inspired me for years. I&rsquo;m entirely in love with the work he and his team is doing. While I don&rsquo;t have any talent for producing designs, I do love art and design. I highly recommend seeing &ldquo;The Happy Show&rdquo; when you have the chance as well as buying <a href="http://amzn.to/2hH78TF">&ldquo;Made you look&rdquo;</a>, a collection of works by Stefan Sagmeister.</p>
<h3 id="may">May</h3>
<p>Mostly filled with work and <a href="https://2017.front-trends.com/">Front-Trends</a>, an amazing conference in Warsaw and also my first time in Warsaw. I spent my time there with my fellow <a href="https://github.com/bullgit/wiki/wiki/Gitch">Gitch</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/mkuehnel">Michael</a>. We had lots of fun and walked around the city to take some pictures and grab foods. Warsaw was astonishing and I would come back every time again!</p>
<h3 id="june-and-july">June and July</h3>
<p>June and July have been calm, beside the <a href="http://www.southside.de/">Southside</a> festival which was canceled due to a storm. Me and the friends I was with spent the night in the car while around us the world was going down - I have never experienced such an intense thunderstorm outside my house.</p>
<p>My highlight in these months was probably the Wedding Party of <a href="https://twitter.com/timpietrusky">Tim</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/FHengesch">Fabienne</a>. It was a wonderful evening with lots of good people and even <a href="https://twitter.com/LukyVj">Luky</a> visited from France!</p>
<p>I also finally got my first tattoo. A cyborg Vault-Boy from Fallout, marking the first tattoo on my left arm which I want to dedicate to video games.</p>
<h3 id="august">August</h3>

<figure >
  

    <img src="/images/posts/2016-review/august-sms.jpg"
      alt="Entrance to Sonne Mond Sterne"
       />
    
  
  <figcaption>
    <p>
      Entrance to Sonne Mond Sterne
      
        
        
    </p> 
  </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<p>In August my girlfriend and I traveled to Amsterdam for a few days to have a good time and enjoy some of the art galleries in Amsterdam. We went to a Banksy exhibition and spent some time inside <a href="https://www.nemosciencemuseum.nl/en/">Nemo</a>, a science museum for kids which can be quite funny.</p>
<p>As every year <a href="https://twitter.com/timpietrusky">Tim</a> and I attended <a href="http://www.sonnemondsterne.de/">Sonne Mond Sterne</a>, an electronic music festival in Germany. To no surprise it was a blast just like the years before and I&rsquo;m already looking forward to 2017!</p>
<h3 id="september">September</h3>
<p>In September we had kind of a <a href="https://twitter.com/bullgit/status/775988689570856960">Bullgit Meetup</a> at <a href="https://viewsourceconf.org/berlin-2016/">viewSource</a> in Berlin. It was great seeing so many Gitches at the same time and being in Berlin is always great! I also visited <a href="https://www.eyeem.com/">EyeEm</a>, one of my favorite Berlin start-ups/companies, and had a little chat about how they grew, how they introduced EyeEm Market and how it is to work with different time zones and large communities. When I first met the EyeEm crew in 2012 they were around 10 or 20 people. It&rsquo;s amazing how they crew both their company and their community over the years. Thanks to EyeEm for having me!</p>
<h3 id="october">October</h3>
<p>In October I saw <a href="https://soundcloud.com/godisanastronaut">God Is An Astronaut</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_QS7z_sGWg&amp;app=desktop">Sounds Like The End Of The World</a>. Both bands have a lot of powered and their music is somewhat &ldquo;trippy&rdquo; - guiding you through extremes and letting you &ldquo;float&rdquo; while listening. For me personally it&rsquo;s already good on tape but astonishing when experienced live. All together it has been 3 or so hours of pure bliss, probably one of the best live concerts I have ever seen.</p>
<h3 id="november">November</h3>
<p>I got new glasses and also went to see &ldquo;20 Years of Placebo&rdquo; with my girlfriend. The concert has been an enjoyment from start to end. They probably played the best songs of the bast 20 years (which makes sense, right?) and also came back on stage 2 or 3 times after the concert ended. It was my first time seeing Placebo live and I would recommend seeing them if they are somewhere near you.</p>
<h3 id="december">December</h3>
<p>Cold days and lots of cozy evenings. I started re-watching Star Trek: The Original Series and I am again madly in love. Given the times when it originally aired on TV and how futuristic it is I dare to say Star Trek is <em>the most amazing Sci-Fi show ever</em>. There you have it.</p>
<p>I also had a great 3 days of Christmas with my girlfriend and the rest of my family. Though I am not religious I like to celebrate Christmas. While I liked it for the presents when I was younger I now like it for the come-together with the family and the foods. It&rsquo;s simply a nice end-of-the-year thing.</p>
<h3 id="all-the-rest">All the rest</h3>
<p>Personal and work-wise 2016 was a success. I had a lot of fun and accomplished some things both private and at work. Sadly, I did not write any blog posts or work on any of my private projects. I had a hard time focusing on development beside work and I felt bad for not doing anything - after some time I ended up in a circle of wanting-to-do-things and feeling depressed for not doing them. For 2017 I want to plan and focus better on private projects, for the most on <a href="https://github.com/kevingimbel/LinedUp">LinedUp</a> which I would like to &ldquo;finish&rdquo;.</p>
<p>What I did in my spare time is Go development. On the search for a new programming language I got a bit into Go and wish to Go Deeper (pun intended!) - I enjoy Go and its strict typed nature is entirely new to me. Let&rsquo;s see how this goes for 2017!</p>
<p>If you made it until here, I wish you a happy 2017! 🎆🎉🍾</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                 
                    
                         
                        
                            
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/review" term="review" label="review" />
                             
                                <category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/personal" term="personal" label="personal" />
                            
                        
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
</feed>
