<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Settings and options!</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/10/new-settings-and-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/10/new-settings-and-options/</guid><description>Over the weekend I implemented a new settings section for my website (the one you read right now!). You can now choose the width of content for articles and pages to better suite your reading preference. I like smaller content because it makes it easier for me to read, others like full-width content. The new settings UI Click the &amp;ldquo;Settings&amp;rdquo; link in the top right and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to configure the randomness of the color schema and the width of content.</description></item><item><title>Keychron K2</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/09/keychron-k2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/09/keychron-k2/</guid><description>Yesterday I got my Keychron K2 keyboard! It&amp;rsquo;s my first time getting a mechanical keyboard and also the first time using an ANSI layout instead of the german ISO layout. It&amp;rsquo;s also the first time using such a small keyboard so I&amp;rsquo;ll need to get used to the position of keys again, especially since I am not typing with 10 fingers (tho I should really learn to!).
I&amp;rsquo;ll need a few weeks before I can give a review but so far I am very happy.</description></item><item><title>2017, week 10, 11, 12, 13</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/04/2017-week-10-11-12-13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2017 13:34:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/04/2017-week-10-11-12-13/</guid><description>Time sure does fly sometimes! I just realized the last &amp;ldquo;weekly&amp;rdquo; review post was from the beginning of march, namely week 8 and 9, so one month ago. In the meantime I played a lot of The Legend Of Zelda: Breath Of The Wild, worked on a Go thing, and went to a concert.
Breath Of The Wild Link looking onto Death Mountain I am absolutely in love with Breath Of The Wild.</description></item><item><title>2017, week 8 and 9</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/03/2017-week-8-and-9/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 19:43:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/03/2017-week-8-and-9/</guid><description>It turns out that a lot of my time is actually spent working or playing games - so there&amp;rsquo;s not too much to tell and weekly updates become hard-ish to write. I am going to go with bi-weekly or even monthly updates from now on. So this post is week eight and week nine - week nine being the week the Nintendo Switch and The Legend Of Zelda: Breath of the Wild were released.</description></item><item><title>2017, week seven</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-seven/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 14:03:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-seven/</guid><description>In week six nothing happened so it was skipped. Quite nice, actually. In the second half of week six and through week seven I prepared a workshop which I gave on Friday at the Coding Night. This Coding Night was a special one: The topic was &amp;ldquo;CodingNight feat. CodeDoor feat. Refugees&amp;rdquo; which was a collaboration between CodingNight and CodeDoor. CodeDoor is a project which teaches Refugees coding skills, how to build projects and how to get a Job in the programming field.</description></item><item><title>2017, week five</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 08:51:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/02/2017-week-five/</guid><description>Another week passed, another personal review. This week I finally got a appointment with my tattoo artist to finish up my tattoo. I&amp;rsquo;m only 6 months late to do so because I kept saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll call next week&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it when I&amp;rsquo;m back from Amsterdam&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll do it after Christmas&amp;rdquo; - and so on. I am really bad with managing time and work-life balance. If you have any tips on how you manage the things you have to do, hit me up on twitter @_kevinatari.</description></item><item><title>2017, week four</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 12:44:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-four/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the last week of the first month already - weird how fast time seems to tick! This week has been rather stressful and loaded with work which is why I did not write any posts or did any programming in my free time. Looking back at the week there&amp;rsquo;s not much to say so this will be a quick read with some reading recommendations at the end.
dep The Go language has released a alpha version of dep - their dependency management tool.</description></item><item><title>2017, week three</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 11:44:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-three/</guid><description>Another week another short review! The third week of 2017 had a lot of travel because I attended an Elasticsearch training course in Munich to learn more about Elasticsearch hands-on. The two day course was exiting and I enjoyed my time, learning quite a lot about the different features of Elasticsearch and Kibana. Part of the course material is a 500 page PDF file which is a copy of the presentation held during the two days - I am glad I got it because it&amp;rsquo;s a great reference to look at.</description></item><item><title>2017, week two</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 17:05:13 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-two/</guid><description>This week I spent a lot of time with Amazon Web Services, or AWS, and made myself familiar with the backend and the way server / instance management works on AWS. While doing so I also learned that AWS instances are by default not accessible from the internet - they have no open ports and each instance needs a &amp;ldquo;Security Group&amp;rdquo; which defines ways to access the instance. They also do not have Shell access by default.</description></item><item><title>2017, week one</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 18:02:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2017-week-one/</guid><description>German blogger, designer, and YouTuber Marcel Wichmann started a weekly-review blog series which I find quite interesting! Reviewing in short what happened in each week of the year is a nice and &amp;ldquo;easy&amp;rdquo; way to recap everything that happened - and it also helps writing this years big review post at the end of the year. I am not sure if I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it up for each week but I will try.</description></item><item><title>2016, a short review</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 14:37:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/2016-a-short-review/</guid><description>2016 has been an odd year in regards to world events and deaths - quite depressing actually. For me personal it has been the exact opposite. Overall, for me 2016 has been an excellent year.
January View from the hotel in Fuerteventura. January started with what we call a &amp;ldquo;Braincamp&amp;rdquo;. A Braincamp is a company trip to a remote location where we at Synoa GmbH take time outside the office and come up with ideas and projects to do for the year.</description></item><item><title>Goodbye Ubuntu, Hello Mac</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/goodbye-ubuntu-hello-mac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 15:05:59 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/goodbye-ubuntu-hello-mac/</guid><description>Christmas came earlier this year! Since my co-workers switched to MacBooks over the year I got a MacBook, too. I got my new PC last year so I was not due to a hardware change for at least another year but - to my luck - I also got a new PC so we all have the same hardware. After three years of Ubuntu and Linux/GNU it&amp;rsquo;s odd to switch to MacOS.</description></item><item><title>How I got employed</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/12/how-i-got-employed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/12/how-i-got-employed/</guid><description>About 1 year ago I joined a tlk.io Chat created by Tim Pietrusky. It was my first time ever I joined a group of other devs and I was more then nervouse about because I - at this time - considered my self more of a Hobby-Dev who&amp;rsquo;s not that skilled. I just started using CodePen a few months before and did some fun demos and experiments there like drawing images with CSS and stuff.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/08/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/08/hello-world/</guid><description>Recently I decided to redesign and redefine my online appearance and the way I publish content to the internet. I switched from using 2 domains as Blog and Portfolio to one new Domain for both: kevingimbel.com
This page is build with Jekyll a blog-aware static site generator you&amp;rsquo;re going to love. I wrote a Guide to get started - so if you consider doing so give it a look.
Beside switching to a new domain I also switched my hoster.</description></item></channel></rss>