<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tools on KevOps</title>
    <link>https://kevingimbel.de/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tools on KevOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into Performance Measurement</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2015/03/getting-into-performance-measurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2015/03/getting-into-performance-measurement/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve spent the past week developing some features for our own website at work. We&#39;re using WordPress and I almost always enjoy working with WordPress beside Magento projects, it&#39;s way easier to keep an overview and with a good overview of data flow and available data it&#39;s easier to measure and find performance bottleneck. In the following post I want to examine my workflow and the way I refactored our code base to increase the speed and overall performance of our site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting into vim - again</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2015/01/getting-into-vim-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2015/01/getting-into-vim-again/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s been some time since I first got my fingers on VIM. My first impression was - as everyones I guess - pretty bad. VIM is not that easy to understand, yet a powerful, shortcut-based, distraction free editor. I&#39;ve already written about turning Sublime Text into VIM mode and my very first VIM impression, but back then I just copy &amp;amp; pasted everything I found on the Internet into my .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Web Developer Tools</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2014/06/useful-web-developer-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2014/06/useful-web-developer-tools/</guid>
      <description>I myself always like to see what other developers use in their workflow: What tools? What plugin? Live-Reload, Pre-Processors, shortcuts - all that stuff. It&#39;s always great to save some time, especially for repeating tasks or challenges. Today I want to share my list of tool that I use on a daily base for all kinds of things.
Browser-based The following tools are all for Chrome because I use Chrome for most of my development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>