<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on KevOps</title>
    <link>https://kevingimbel.de/categories/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on KevOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 15:05:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Ubuntu, Hello Mac</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/goodbye-ubuntu-hello-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 15:05:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/goodbye-ubuntu-hello-mac/</guid>
      <description>Christmas came earlier this year! Since my co-workers switched to MacBooks over the year I got a MacBook, too. I got my new PC last year so I was not due to a hardware change for at least another year but - to my luck - I also got a new PC so we all have the same hardware. After three years of Ubuntu and Linux/GNU it&amp;rsquo;s odd to switch to MacOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Development in 2014</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2014/01/web-development-in-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2014/01/web-development-in-2014/</guid>
      <description>As soon as you start to really dig into web development it feels like things would change daily - at least I feel that way. But there&amp;rsquo;s one thing that I&amp;rsquo;d like everyone to do in 2014: At least basic responsive web development to ensure your site - at least - looks good and is usable on whatever screen it will be displayed. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing I hate more than scrolling websites around on my phone when I want to read an article (to be honest, I mostly leave the site and never come back).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I got employed</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/12/how-i-got-employed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/12/how-i-got-employed/</guid>
      <description>About 1 year ago I joined a tlk.io Chat created by Tim Pietrusky. It was my first time ever I joined a group of other devs and I was more then nervouse about because I - at this time - considered my self more of a Hobby-Dev who&amp;rsquo;s not that skilled. I just started using CodePen a few months before and did some fun demos and experiments there like drawing images with CSS and stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join a Dev Group</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/10/join-a-dev-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/10/join-a-dev-group/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this year I joined a Dev Group. It was the best decision I made this year and I want to tell you why. After doing more experiments on CodePen and right after I got to know Tim Pietrusky he opened a tlk.io Chat called #CodePen. For those who&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with tlk: it&amp;rsquo;s an open web chat. You can create a room, everyone can join and all things are open to everyone who knows the URL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Endless scrolling</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/09/endless-scrolling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2013/09/endless-scrolling/</guid>
      <description>If you see Apps (no matter if native or web) and websites like I do, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably now the worst thing that can happen to an endless scrolling page: No shortcut to get back to top. Even Facebook doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer a way to get back to top on their website nor do they on Facebook for Android.
On Android you can simply hit the menu button and the sidebar-like menu will fade in, so there is no problem with not having an &amp;ldquo;scroll to top&amp;rdquo; action because there is no need to get back to the top.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>