<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scripting on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</title>
    <link>https://kevingimbel.de/tags/scripting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scripting on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en_US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/scripting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grep in Action</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/11/grep-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/11/grep-in-action/</guid>
      <description>grep is a CLI tool created in 1974 that is pre-installed on any Linux/Unix-like/BSD* system. grep is an acronym and stands for _&amp;ldquo;globally search for a regular expression and print matching lines&amp;rdquo;_ - quite a mouth full but a good description of what grep does. The more I worked in the Sys-/DevOps domain, the more I found myself using grep and awk to select parts of files for further processing. In this article I want to highlight some things grep can do that _I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about but wish I did_ when I started using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash script: ws</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/bash-script-ws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 19:22:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2017/01/bash-script-ws/</guid>
      <description>For the past year or so I had a little function in my .bash_profile file which made my interaction with the terminal roughly 9001% better - yeah, over 9000! This little function is called ws and makes switching between projects inside my workspace a lot easier. Both my private and work projects are inside the ~/Development directory. If I want to get to a project I would normally navigate like cd ~/Development/private/github/kevingimbel/kevingimbel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
