<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>netflix on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/tags/netflix/</link><description>Recent content in netflix on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en_US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/netflix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hannah Gadsby - Douglas</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/09/hannah-gadsby-douglas/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/09/hannah-gadsby-douglas/</guid><description>Last night my wife and I watched Hannah Gadsbys newest stand-up show called &amp;ldquo;Douglas&amp;rdquo; and within the first minute I was out of breath and laughing because she just hits my humor spot on. Absolutely loved this show! It&amp;rsquo;s a good hour of laughing with serious topics wrapped into jokes, but never feels too uncomfortable.
From the topics and the overall feeling it&amp;rsquo;s not as hard as Nanette, which just left me sobbing during the last half and was a constant rollercoaster because it is very harsh and real and touches a lot of very personal topics; If you haven&amp;rsquo;t watched it I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spoil - just take an hour and watch it on Netflix.</description></item><item><title>Night on Earth</title><link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/04/night-on-earth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/04/night-on-earth/</guid><description>Last weekend I finished &amp;ldquo;Night on Earth&amp;rdquo; a Netflix documentation about animal life during the night, filmed with super light sensitive cameras making the darkest night look like early evening; It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting look into the night and quite entertaining and educating.
You can find the documentation here on Netflix
★★★★☆</description></item></channel></rss>