<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>magento on Portfolio and blog of Kevin Gimbel, DevOps Engineer and Full-Stack Developer</title>
    <link>https://www.kevingimbel.de/tags/magento/</link>
    <description>Recent content in magento on Portfolio and blog of Kevin Gimbel, DevOps Engineer and Full-Stack Developer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.kevingimbel.de/tags/magento/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento: Add fields to the Admin Backend</title>
      <link>https://www.kevingimbel.de/2014/08/magento-add-fields-to-the-admin-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kevingimbel.de/2014/08/magento-add-fields-to-the-admin-backend/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a task at work that first sounded rather easy: Add a field to the Admin backend, namely System-&amp;gt;Config-&amp;gt;Catalog where the user could later insert some SKUs to control which products are shown on the home page. The first resources I found on how to edit the Backend where all suggesting to create a Module and then create a settings page. Not only was this rather complex it was also way too &amp;ldquo;over engineered&amp;rdquo; for a simple thing like a text field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magento: get and set variables in config.xml</title>
      <link>https://www.kevingimbel.de/2014/05/magento-get-and-set-variables-in-config.xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kevingimbel.de/2014/05/magento-get-and-set-variables-in-config.xml/</guid>
      <description>The other day I had a kind of easy problem in Magento that still took me quite some time to solve. In the shop I&#39;m working on we had a contact form module that sents and validates emails which worked perfectly fine on one page (the one it was made for), however this form should be &amp;ldquo;cloned&amp;rdquo; to be present on 4 pages with different email addresses. Since Magentos Core is MVC-like I believed there would be an easy way to pass email addresses to the Controller.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>