<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>android on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</title>
    <link>https://kevingimbel.de/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in android on KevOps — DevOps, Cooking, and everything else I want to write about</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en_US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Two Factor Auth, Password managers, and cloud sync</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/01/two-factor-auth-password-managers-and-cloud-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2020/01/two-factor-auth-password-managers-and-cloud-sync/</guid>
      <description>For years I have not given much thought to passwords, security, or how to manage my passwords efficiently and securely. I usually would either save them in the browser or just re-use passwords (which of course is the worst). Around 7-8ish years ago I began to use password managers and password generators, and when 2FA became a more common thing I was enabling that on all services I could. 2FA (Two Factor Authentication) is a method of authentication where two parts are needed: A Password and a generated token, this token can be hardware based (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snippet: theme-color for Android 5.0</title>
      <link>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2014/11/snippet-theme-color-for-android-5.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2014/11/snippet-theme-color-for-android-5.0/</guid>
      <description>Just yesterday I got my Android 5.0 update which also features a new way multi-tasking works and Chrome interacts with this multi-tasking. In fact, all recently opened tabs are available via the multi-tasking button (square to the down right on Stock Android) instead of an in-app button like it used to be. This not only is very handy actually since you can switch between apps and websites seamlessly you can also set your own status bar colors for chrome which are used on the page and in the multi-tasking overview.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
