<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en_US"><generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.72.0">Hugo</generator><title type="html">hardware on KevOps</title><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/hardware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="HTML"/><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="alternate" type="application/rss+xml" title="RSS"/><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/hardware/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" title="Atom"/><updated>2020-08-17T11:01:23+02:00</updated><id>https://kevingimbel.de/tags/hardware/</id><entry><title type="html">Goodbye Ubuntu, Hello Mac</title><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/goodbye-ubuntu-hello-mac/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/gotcha-dockerignore/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Gotcha: dockerignore"/><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/11/farewell-jekyll-hello-hugo/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Farewell Jekyll, Hello Hugo"/><link href="https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2015/12/speed-up-your-jekyll-workflow/?utm_source=atom_feed" rel="related" type="text/html" title="Speed up your Jekyll workflow"/><id>https://kevingimbel.de/blog/2016/12/goodbye-ubuntu-hello-mac/</id><published>2016-12-27T15:05:59+01:00</published><updated>2016-12-27T15:05:59+01:00</updated><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Christmas came earlier this year! Since my co-workers switched to MacBooks over the year I got a MacBook, too. I got my new PC last year so I was not due to a hardware change for at least another year but - to my luck - I also got a new PC so we all have the same hardware. After three years of Ubuntu and Linux/GNU it&rsquo;s odd to switch to MacOS. While MacOS is closer to Unix-like systems it&rsquo;s still closed and not as open as Ubuntu or other Linux/GNU distributions. Changing Laptops is hard enough but changing operating systems - and changing to a system one has never worked with is a different thing. For documentation and to help others, I would like to document what I noticed when switching and how I got up and running in a week.</p>
<h3 id="dotfiles">~/dotfiles</h3>
<p>I have a <a href="https://github.com/kevingimbel/dotfiles">GitHub repository</a> with dotfiles. By checking out the repository and linking the files I was able to setup my terminal in a few minutes. The repository is not perfect yet and there are unused files which I should - and will - clean-up. Nevertheless without the configs I would have needed to copy the files or re-configure everything by hand.</p>
<h3 id="docker">Docker</h3>
<p>Currently we at <a href="https://synoa.de">Synoa</a> move projects to <a href="https://docker.com">Docker</a> for local development and - in a selected way - for production, too. The basic benefits of Docker for Development show right when creating the first containers - one can replicate the production servers without a lot of hassle: operating systems and software versions can be defined on a per-project basis. One project is build on PHP 5.6, the other on 7.0 - with Docker we don&rsquo;t need to maintain different PHP versions on computers. It&rsquo;s just a small benefit but it&rsquo;s also a &ldquo;easy&rdquo; way to share projects. I am still learning Docker and Docker best practice - as I learn more I will cover it in articles.</p>
<h3 id="operating-system">Operating System</h3>
<p>MacOS is really beautiful. The user interface is a joy to work with and the gestures used to switch between tabs and workspaces is astonishing - it feels productive and it&rsquo;s fun to use. I really enjoy just working with it simply because of the Design. The Linux base of MacOS is visible when navigation with the Terminal - it does not feel odd and most of the software I used on Ubuntu when interacting with the file system is &ldquo;the same&rdquo;. <code>grep</code>, <code>ls</code>, <code>head</code>, <code>tail</code>, <code>cat</code> - all these utilities work as expected. The only noticeable difference is <code>sed</code>. On Ubuntu I used <code>sed</code> a lot to clean SQL dumps, for example <code>sed -i 's/domain\.tld/domain\.local/g' mydump.sql</code> - this replaces <code>domain.tld</code> with <code>domain.local</code> inside the SQL dump. On MacOS one must add a post-fix for a backup file when using <code>sed</code>. The sed command becomes <code>sed -i '.bak' 's/domain\.tld/domain\.local/g' mydump.sql</code> and a backup file <code>mydump.sql.bak</code> is created. It&rsquo;s just a small difference but it caught me off-guard when I noticed bash scripts failing.</p>
<h3 id="hardware">Hardware</h3>
<p><strong>A-ma-zing</strong>! I expected a lot from a MacBook and I was blown away. The MacBook Pro feels good to the touch, it&rsquo;s well made and the Design aspect is visible in the choices of material and colors. While mine is not too high-end it still runs smootly and the battery life is unbelievable. Without a second display connected I get around 7-9 hours of battery life when writing or programming (no IDE used, just <a href="https://atom.io">Atom</a>) - when I have 30% battery left I can still work without running to plug it in. Even at 5%, when the Mac tells me to plug the cable in, I still have time left and can get the cable.</p>
<h3 id="software">Software</h3>
<p>I am currently figuring out which software I need and which software I want. I installed <a href="https://docs.docker.com/engine/installation/mac/">Docker for Mac</a>, <a href="https://atom.io">Atom</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/">Chrome</a> and the usual things like Google Drive and <a href="https://www.keepassx.org/">KeyPassX</a>. I switched away from the default Terminal to <a href="https://www.iterm2.com/">iTerm 2</a>, but besides I kept it vanilla and did not install unnecessary software.</p>
<p>Did I miss a thing? <a href="https://twitter.com/_kevinatari">Tweet me @_kevinatari</a> and tell me what I absolutely need!</p>
]]></content><category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/personal" term="personal" label="personal"/><category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/categories/thoughts" term="thoughts" label="thoughts"/><category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/hardware" term="hardware" label="hardware"/><category scheme="https://kevingimbel.de/tags/development" term="development" label="development"/></entry></feed>